# LORISMAE SHIELDA P. ARCILLA

(+63) 9176235456 | Iorismaearcilla@outlook.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/lorismaearcilla

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Senior Quality Assurance (QA) Engineer with an extensive experience in software testing for manual and automation test environment in the field of telecommunications and information technology. Experienced in software development life cycle, including analyzing, designing, and implementing test plans, test cases, and test processes following Agile methodology. Demonstrated skills in leading and mentoring team members, while also proactively taking responsibilities with a proven ability in meeting targets and ensuring outstanding quality deliverables. Dependable, attentive, and organized team player with the capability to communicate, identify, and implement improvement ideas, which help achieve team goals effectively and efficiently.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Collabera Digital, Ayala Ave., Makati City

A digital engineering company that creates unique experiences, provides actionable insights, and develops intelligent products and platforms by combining talent and technology.

G-Xchange, Inc., Bonifacio Global City, Taguig City (November 2023 – May 2024)

## **Lead Quality Assurance Engineer**

Primarily engaged in design and development sprints. Responsible for conducting comprehensive test analysis, leading test analysis walkthroughs, reviewing and approving test cases, managing end-to-end testing activities, ensuring adherence to project timelines, and leading post-production testing efforts. Additionally, documented bug reports and collaborated with cross-functional teams to resolve issues.

#### **Key Accomplishments**

• Led successful production deployments and post-production testing, working closely with stakeholders to identify and resolve issues, ensuring corrective actions were implemented when necessary.

Maya Philippines, Inc., Sheridan cor. Reliance St., Mandaluyong City (May 2021 – May 2023)

#### **Senior Quality Engineer**

Built test automation using Python Behave Framework. Maintained and executed manual and automated tests including security testing. Created and designed test plans and test cases for verification. Reported defects and verified fixes. Coordinated and worked with the development team and product management to implement services and plan testing activities and release efforts. Facilitated and led scrum events. Mentored and trained team members related to testing services.

#### **Key Accomplishments**

- Designed and created comprehensive test cases as part of the migration of services and the onboarding of new remittance partner for Maya Philippines' remittance platform, wherein critical defects were caught and raised to the development team.
- Owned the development of test automation scripts to verify the test cases created for each testing phase in different environment instance.
- Took the initiative to improve the implementation of existing automation tests for each remittance service resulting to full automation testing, reduction in test execution time, and smooth flow in testing the services.
- Owned the regression testing for the new card management system focusing on transaction reports for issuing
  payment services. Created new test suites that would maximize regression testing activities while ensuring
  rigorous testing is done, which resulted to numerous defects caught and reported.
- Led testing activities related to production issues raised on top of other testing responsibilities.
- Organized and improved test data used for each environment instance by consolidating test accounts and details for easier team access and usage.

# Nokia Technology Center Philippines, Inc., Commonwealth Ave., Quezon City

A Finnish multinational telecommunication company that offers comprehensive portfolio of network equipment, software, services and licensing opportunities across the world.

#### **Software Quality Assurance Engineer** (January 2017 – June 2020)

Executed manual and automation testing to verify and ensure outstanding quality in the functionality of software releases

on WCDMA Base Transceiver Stations (WBTS), which also includes hardware setup, commissioning, and configuring WBTS. Performed new feature analysis and designed necessary test plans and test cases based on user stories for verification. Coordinated with project manager, product owner, and scrum master for project execution and problem report discussion and resolution. Provided direction and support to team members in the areas of technical issues and problems, processes, and operations. Facilitated and led scrum events such as sprint planning, daily scrum, sprint review, and sprint retrospective.

# **Key Accomplishments**

- Achieved 20% reduction of test execution time for daily regression testing by optimizing the test automation
  and integrating the old manual test steps to the test automation, resulting to 100% test automation for daily
  regression testing to fully comply with the 24-hour cycle, which is from test execution to test result reporting.
- Took the responsibility to be the Feature Owner (FO) for three (3) newly introduced features. Thorough
  testability analysis and test planning were done accordingly to ensure the coverage for testing, which led to
  numerous faults reported, yet still managed to deliver on time by proactively communicating with project
  management team, software development team, and other testing teams.
- Ensured outstanding quality software is promoted and delivered by thorough testing, reporting and closing faults. Thus, was recognized for two (2) consecutive years as one of the testers with the highest number of faults reported in our competence area, which also led to be recognized in the tribe level.
- Identified and implemented improvement ideas, which helped the team work more efficiently such as:
  - Drove the optimization of test cases and test environments to cover a broader testing scope, resulting to 100% test coverage of high priority customer configurations.
  - Initiated and led RNC clean-up for IPBR IDs to have an organized naming convention and specific ID for each WBTS, aligning it also in the Single IP Migration implemented in WBTS I&V Team.
  - Organized and improved reference documents useful for testing and created troubleshooting and test guides that are helpful as it promotes and encourages the team to have confidence and independence in executing test cases especially the newcomers.

#### Customer Documentation (CuDo) - Technical Writer (September 2013 – January 2017)

Created, edited, and maintained customer documentation for Nokia's WCDMA RNC and LTE products, which includes feature descriptions, feature activation instructions, functional area descriptions, and system descriptions. Performed internal testing of new LTE features using the BTS Site Manager (BTSSM).

#### Key Accomplishments

- Contributed to the very first rich media created in one of the LTE features handled to be launched in CuDo. The introduction of rich media in CuDo is for the end user to understand the information easier in an interactive way.
- Successfully delivered a program milestone despite the challenges encountered due to sudden transfer of project to Manila CuDo team without formal knowledge transfer.
- Managed to learn quality assurance and software testing through self-study, online trainings, and shadowing with an Integration & Verification Test Engineer.

#### **EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL LICENSE**

Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Communications Engineering, April 2012

Holy Angel University, Angeles City

Professional Regulation Commission - Board of Electronics Engineering, Reg. No. 0051704

#### **CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAININGS**

CI Drive Practitioner (July 2019) | Lean and Kaizen Advocate (June 2019) | Certified SAFe 4 Practitioner Scaled Agile, Inc. (October 2018) | Purple Badge Recognition (November 2016) | Agile - Certified Scrum Master Training (September 2016) | Root Cause Analysis and Escaped Defects Analysis for SW and HW Workshop (July 2016) | Design Failure Mode & Effects Analysis Workshop (July 2016)

#### SKILLS

#### **Technical and Soft Skills**

Agile Software Development | Python | SQL | Black-box Testing | API Testing | Technical Analysis | Troubleshooting | Root Cause Analysis and Escaped Defects Analysis | Process Improvements | Problem Solving | Leadership/Mentoring | Time Management | Mobile Networks (UMTS/LTE)

## **Tools and Environment**

HP ALM Quality Center | JIRA | PyCharm | Postman | GIT | GitLab | DBeaver | Oracle SQL Developer | Burp Suite Professional | Behave Framework | Card Management System | Confluence | SharePoint | Microsoft Teams